learningplanet.com 2000-06-01

# Learning Planet Privacy Statement

Everything we do at Lightspan, Inc. is built on one idea: finding ways to help students—every one of them—perform at their very best. To help meet this goal, we provide a family of Internet sites and services. Lightspan is firmly committed to the privacy and security of all online visitors to our sites; we understand that our visitors and registered members need to be in control of their personal information. This policy statement tells you how and why we collect information from you, and how we use that information. 

We encourage our visitors to read through and understand our entire Privacy Policy. Please contact us at [contactus@lightspan.com](mailto:contactus@lightspan.com) if you have any questions about it. However, to quickly access a particular section of the Policy, you can click directly on the links below.   

  1. Sites and Services to Which This Statement Applies
  2. Information You Provide to Us
  3. General Information About Visitors to Our Site
  4. Links to Other Sites
  5. The Lightspan Learning Store and Lightspan PageOne
  6. Security
  7. Policies for Children Under Age 13
  8. Policies for Teens Age 13 Through 17
  9. Choice/Opt-Out/Update
  10. Contact Us

  1. **Sites and Services to Which This Statement Applies**

This statement discloses the privacy practices for all Lightspan, Inc.'s, Web sites and services. Those Web sites and services include: 

| 

Academic.com  
Ed-Mail  
Global Schoolhouse  
Lightspan.com  
LearningPlanet.com 

|  |  The Lightspan Network  
Lightspan PageOne  
StudyWeb  
Your Class Online  
Your School Online  
---|---|---  
  
The information you provide when you register with any of these Lightspan sites or services may be shared with the other Lightspan sites or services, since it will make your visits to our sites easier and save you the inconvenience of re-registering. Any reference to "we," "us," "Lightspan," or "Lightspan, Inc.," in this statement applies to all the Web sites and services above. 

  2. **Information You Provide to Us**

**When We Collect Information From You**  
We want to present information on Lightspan sites that's tailored to your needs. So we may ask you to register or to provide personal information when you visit certain areas of our sites, enter a contest or sweepstakes, play games, complete surveys, submit content, subscribe to a newsletter or ask us for additional information. 

We only collect personally identifiable information from you when you voluntarily submit it. Providing your personally identifiable information to Lightspan is optional for using Lightspan.com, Global Schoolhouse, and StudyWeb. If you choose not to register or provide your personal information, you can still visit these sites. However, you won't have access to areas that require personal identification, such as chat rooms and posting to message boards. 

We also ask for personal identification from visitors wishing to establish password-protected sites with us, such as Your Class Online and Your School Online, and to establish a subscription to The Lightspan Network. Lightspan collects this information for administrative purposes, for tracking/verifying compliance with Lightspan policies as well as applicable laws, for editorial and feedback solicitation purposes, and/or fulfilling prizes. 

Lightspan may occasionally present a special contest or promotion that's sponsored by another company. To qualify for entry, we may ask you to provide personal information. If we plan to share that information with the sponsor(s), we'll let you know when we request your information. We may use your personal information to "fulfill," e.g. to deliver a given prize should you be a winner, in which case we may share your information with an outside fulfillment vendor which will deliver your prize. 

If you don't want Lightspan, our partners, or selected third parties to contact you, you may opt out when you provide personal information, or contact us directly to let us know. For instructions on how to do so, please see the [Contact Us](http://www.lightspan.com/community/pages/help/contactus.asp?_prod=LS&_nav=n1_emailus) section below. In case you change your mind or some of your personal information changes (such as your phone number or ZIP code), we'll endeavor to provide a way to correct, update, or remove the personal data you give us. You can do this at the member information page or by contacting our Privacy Coordinator at [contactus@lightspan.com](mailto:contactus@lightspan.com). 

**What Information We Collect**  
Depending on the particular Lightspan site with which you initially register, we may ask for your name, age, address, telephone, e-mail address, and school details (name of school, position, and/or grade level.) If you're under 18 years of age, we'll also ask you to provide your parent's or guardian's e-mail address. (A separate section of this privacy statement specifically addresses our privacy policies for Children Under Age 13.) We'll also ask you to select a user name and password to use when you log in to our site. 

**How We Use the Information You Give Us**  
We use the personal information you provide us to tailor the content, services and advertising on our Web sites to your current and future needs. For the same reason, we may share the personal information you provide to us with third parties who are affiliated with our sites, or who provide services to our sites. 

We also use visitor login information to help us ensure that our members only see and use appropriate areas of our Web sites. For example, members under age 13 are only permitted to post on certain message boards and not any others, and only authorized members are permitted to access Your Class Online clubs. 

If you provide us with your mailing address or telephone number, we and our partners may use this information to alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information, and new services. If you provide your e-mail address, we may contact you via e-mail as well. 

Lightspan sometimes supplements the information that visitors provide with information that we get from third parties. For example, when visitors provide a ZIP code, we combine that information with a database of schools in that ZIP code to offer the visitor a convenient way to select the school with which they are affiliated. 

In addition, in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture or other transfer or disposition of some or all of the assets of Lightspan, Inc., or its affiliated entities, you agree that we can accordingly assign, sell, license or transfer any information, including personally identifying information, that our visitors have provided to us to third parties. 

Lightspan may disclose visitor information in special cases when we have reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Lightspan's rights or property, other Lightspan visitors or members, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. Lightspan may disclose visitor information when we believe in good faith that the law requires us to do so. 

  3. **General Information About Visitors to Our Site**

**Aggregate Information**  
Lightspan shares aggregate information about our visitors and members with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. For example, we may say that Lightspan's audience is "x" percent teachers and "y" percent parents. We use this information to customize our content and advertising to deliver a better experience for our visitors and members. 

**Cookies**  
The use of cookies is common in the Internet industry; you'll find them used on our Web sites, as you will at other major sites. "Cookies" are small text files written to your computer. They make our Web sites easier for you to use because they save your preferences while you're at our sites (although we do not save passwords in cookies.) Cookies also help us know which areas are your favorites, which need a bit of improvement, and what technologies and Internet services our visitors are using. Knowing this information helps us continually improve the online experience for our visitors and members. 

The non-personally identifying information we track with cookies is anonymous and is not used to identify, or lead us back to, any particular visitor. Visitors to our sites may have the option of disabling cookies via their browser preferences (most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies.) However, some features of our Web sites won't function properly or may be considerably slower if you refuse cookies. For example, without cookies you may have difficulty entering contests or playing games. 

While browsing our Web sites, you may get cookies from our advertisers or sponsors. Lightspan and its affiliated sites do not control these cookies. 

**IP Addresses**  
An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you use the World Wide Web. Web servers—the big computers that "serve up" Web pages—automatically identify your computer by its IP address. 

Lightspan collects IP addresses for system administration; to report aggregate information to our advertisers, sponsors, and partners; and to audit the use of our site. When visitors request pages from Lightspan sites, our servers log the guests' IP addresses. We normally do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that a visitor's session will be logged, but the visitor remains anonymous to us. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a visitor when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our rules or terms of service, or to protect our service, site, customers, or others. 

Some features within Lightspan, such as certain message boards, may display IP addresses along with the message-poster's visitor name and message. You should review each feature prior to use and only use those that disclose information you're comfortable sharing. 

**Electronic Postcards**  
We give visitors the option to send "electronic postcards." We ask you to submit the e-mail address of your intended recipient so that we can send the postcard to them for you. We don't store your recipient's e-mail address in retrievable form, and we don't use it for marketing or any other purpose beyond delivering the electronic postcard at your request. 

  4. **Links to Other Sites**

You'll find links from Lightspan sites to independently owned, controlled, and/or managed Web sites whose content we believe will be of possible interest and value to our visitors. Additionally, you'll see links from advertisers, sponsors, and other partners who may use Lightspan's logo as part of a co-branding agreement (such as the Lightspan Learning Store and Lightspan PageOne.) 

In many cases, these links represent cooperative projects or mutual links established with the organizations connected with these sites. We don't control the content of these links. For example, if you click a Learning Search result or banner advertisement, that click takes you off the Lightspan site. These other sites may send you their own cookies, collect data, or solicit personal information. While we identify sponsor and advertiser areas of our Web sites, we do not control these cookies or the content of these third parties. 

Once you leave our servers (you can generally tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser,) the use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you're visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from that site's Home page, you should contact the site directly for more information. 

We specifically recommend that children check with their parents or teachers before clicking on to any new sites. 

  5. **The Lightspan Learning Store and Lightspan PageOne**

**The Lightspan Learning Store**  
Lightspan, Inc. has a relationship with online educational retailer SmarterKids.com through which we offer the SmarterKids product mix as the primary resource for educational products on Lightspan sites. This partnership offers Lightspan's community of parents and teachers ready access to a range of information and quality educational products that complement what a child is learning in school. Purchasing products from the Lightspan Learning Store requires you to register separately with SmarterKids. When you do, SmarterKids will ask you to provide personally identifiable information so that it can bill you and fulfill your order. Lightspan and its sites are not involved with this purchase process. Consult the SmarterKids Privacy Policy for more information. 

**Lightspan PageOne**  
Lightspan, Inc. has a relationship with Yahoo! through which we offer Lightspan PageOne (free classroom Web-site clubs.) Establishing a PageOne club requires you to register with both Lightspan and Yahoo!. The information you provide to Yahoo! is governed by Yahoo!'s privacy policy, which you should consult for more information. In addition, Lightspan will share your personal information with Yahoo! so they can administer your club and allow only you and your authorized club members to access your club. 

  6. **Security**

The importance of security for your personally identifiable information is of utmost concern to us. We have systems in place to assist us in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Lightspan can't and doesn't ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. 

Your Class Online, Your School Online, The Lightspan Network and Lightspan PageOne accounts are all password-protected so that only authorized members are permitted to access them or view the member information relevant to the account. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Lightspan does not ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or e-mail. Ultimately, you are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and any account information. 

Remember to sign out of your Lightspan password-protected account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if your computer is accessible to others, or if you share a computer with someone else, or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafŽ. 

Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information online—for example, via message boards or chat—that information can be collected and used by people you don't know. While Lightspan strives to protect its visitors' personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online and you do so at your own risk. 

Lightspan's policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond Lightspan's control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation. 

  7. **Policies for Children Under Age 13**

Lightspan and its affiliated Web sites encourage parents to be involved with and aware of their children's online experience. Members under 13 years of age shouldn't submit or post information at Lightspan Web sites without the consent of their parent or guardian. 

Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, Lightspan does not provide any personally identifying information, regardless of its source, to any third party, for any purpose whatsoever from our members under 13 years of age. We don't use any information collected from visitors under 13 years of age for any marketing or promotional purposes whatsoever, either inside or outside Lightspan, except as we explicitly state during registration for contests or promotions. In that case, the information collected is used only for the specific contest or promotion. 

All members receive an e-mail confirming their registration. In addition, when a visitor under 13 registers with any of our sites, he/she is required to provide the e-mail address of his/her parent or guardian. We then send that parent or guardian an e-mail alerting them to the child's registration and giving them the chance to cancel the registration and ask that the child's information be deleted from our records. 

Members under age 13 do not have access to Lightspan chat rooms or message boards (except those that are pre-moderated and specifically directed to children,) and cannot create a Your Class Online, Your School Online, Lightspan Network, Ed-Mail or Lightspan PageOne account. Lightspan community policy experts monitor all of our free interactive activities accessible to members under 13 years of age. Therefore, children may participate in such activities upon registration, unless their parent or guardian asks that their registration be invalidated. 

Although visitors under 13 years of age may be allowed to participate in some contests and promotions, if such a visitor wins, notification and prizes are sent to the parents or guardians identified in the initial registration process. Publication of contest winners names, ages, or images for individuals under 13 requires parental or guardian consent. 

Lightspan will not require a child under 13 to disclose more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in an activity as a condition of participation. 

  8. **Policies for Teens Age 13 Through 17**

Teens age 13-17 are required to provide the e-mail address of a parent or guardian when they register at our sites. We then e-mail a notification message to the teen's parent or guardian that identifies the information supplied at registration. 

Teens age 13-17 are _not_ eligible to establish password-protected pages using Your Class Online, Your School Online or Lightspan PageOne. 

  9. **Choice/Opt-Out/Update**

You can help Lightspan maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your address, title, phone number, or e-mail address. Please include your old and new contact information so that we can make the appropriate corrections. 

Information provided at the time of registration or submission from a visitor who is 13 years of age or over may be used for marketing and promotional purposes by Lightspan, Inc., and our affiliates, or companies that have been prescreened by us. However, you can request not to receive communications from us about new features or services. You can also ask not to receive communications from third-party companies that offer a product or service that we think would be of value to you. If you object to such use for any reason, you can e-mail your request to [contactus@lightspan.com](mailto:contactus@lightspan.com) or modify your member information online. 

  10. **Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy statement, you should contact the company as follows: Privacy Policy Coordinator, Lightspan, Inc., 2001 Wilshire Boulevard, Suite 301, Santa Monica, CA 90403; telephone number (888) 4-ALL-KIDS; or via e-mail at [contactus@lightspan.com](mailto:contactus@lightspan.com). Return to top of page 

**Your Acceptance of These Terms**

By using this Web site, you signify your consent to Lightspan, Inc.'s, Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this, please do not use our Web sites or services. Your continued use of Lightspan, Inc.'s, Web sites or services following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes in accordance with the [Terms of Use](http://www.lightspan.com/community/pages/help/termsofuse.asp?_prod=LS&_nav=n1_termsofuse).
